Hey, uh, what's all this?
It's that little girl. She has returned. Fapta, that is.
Fapta.
What the? I remember.
I had you breathe in my experiences.
Smells are memories themselves, and like dreams, they are volatile.
But I do hope that they touched you.
Why would you do that?
Like all things, I must go.
And so, Nanachi, I've entrusted you with both my value and memories.
I like you, kids. You are not like me.
And that is the reason why.
Where's Riko? And where's Rek?
They are still here.
However, Fapta will not stop until she burns everything to ash.
You should go. I have already released you.
You can go wherever you please now.
You're fine with that?
Well, then, I think I'll go before you change your mind.
Thanks for your help.
Nanachi, over there.
That is the boundary line.
If you pass through it, Mithi will disappear.
Wait, what?
What are you saying?
I mean, Mithi's immortal, isn't she?
That which has been created inside the village can only exist within the village.
As I was created as the village's limbs, I am capable of enduring some, but there are no exceptions.
Beyond that point, the protection of the village melts away.
This area will not last long either.
The force field is creeping in.
If you remain here, I shall do my utmost to protect you.
Well, I see Piggymule and the others have also taken a liking to you.
Rico.
Wreck.
Damn it.
Isn't there something I can do?
I mean, I so wanted to see Mithi.
I didn't think I could ever see her again.
Mithi.
What should I do?
This Mithi, you know, is still the same Mithi from before Bondaroon.
She was hurt in so many ways.
In her cute little pot.
She's beautiful like this.
I was just so happy.
So I got the wrong idea.
I thought we could stay here together forever.
Even though I know I didn't receive this body.
Just to lie around and sleep about.
Those memories I shared with you put you to sleep.
That's okay.
Either way, I would have chosen to stay by Mithi's side.
That's the way I am.
I know that about myself.
Belov, I'll be going now.
I made a promise with Mithi.
That if things turned out like this, I'd make it so her soul returns to me.
I don't want to do anything else that might make Mithi grow to hate me.
This time, I can see her off by my own hand.
Goodbye, Belov.
Thanks for taking a liking to my...
my Mithi.
Mithi, listen.
I learned how to cook some new dishes.
They come out looking all crazy.
But they're unbelievably tasty.
Oh, and I made friends I'm going adventuring with.
They both know about you and what you mean.
I am...
Well, you know...
I wish...
I wish that I could have talked to you more.
And if I ever...
If I ever find you in your current form again, I'm sure...
I won't know what to do then, too.
So next time, really scold me, okay?
Next time, we'll go together.
It will eat some yummy stuff.
I'll be...
sure to find you again.
I'll definitely go and see you, Mithi.
So then...
So please...
Please wait for me.
What are you guys doing?
Mithi!
Made for you with outside stuff, so that it don't disappear.
Take with you.
Longing.
Impurity.
Joy.
Pain.
I have cast them all away.
Pick them up.
And carry them with you.
All that you gather...
Is your value.
Thank goodness you're all right.
Reg, you woke up!
Sorry.
Thank goodness you're all right.
It's you!
It protected us.
It made sure we didn't get caught up in all the mayhem.
Thank you for that.
Reg, neither Fopta nor the village will stop.
Reg, the eternal peace has been broken.
You made the choice not to leave.
Now is the time to show your resolve.
Reg, if we don't do something fast.
The things everyone treasures, and the ones they hold dear will...
The light, large and bright, shines with undying curiosity and a hallowed curtain.
It burns all it gazes upon.
It has now become a scorching sun.
It is time to face it.
Show your resolve.
Ow.
Oh.
It's so funny.
Gah.
I'm so paraphrasing.
Ah!
Inbelieve!
Ani!
Emigutsu!
The balancing is making the villagers eat into each other.
It's even spreading to the buildings.
And the walls.
Guess we've got about another 30 minutes.
This will be difficult.
What do you mean?
What'll be difficult?
I can't tell you.
You know how bad at lying I am.
Greg, those guys.
It was all thanks to them I was able to survive.
If this keeps up, everyone's treasured things on themselves.
Oh, Riko.
You did a really good job.
You didn't rush into things.
I am going to stop, Fapta.
Well, Prince, everything hinges on you and what you do now.
I'm sorry, Fapta.
A member of our team, Nanachi, is being held captive.
Please don't destroy any more of the village.
Go and save Nanachi.
Fapta won't stop you.
Don't use your friend as an excuse.
You try not to hurt Fapta.
So you lie to me again, Sosu?
Come out and say it, Sosu.
What is it you want?
Sorry for being selfish.
But Fapta, I will stop you.
And I will save Nanachi!
Reg, you are kind, Sosu.
If you are to do it, it is better to take me by surprise.
Understood.
Then Fapta will make you remember what you are meant to do.
Even if it means beating you into nothing, Sosu!
Answer me!
Come on, Gabu!
You are supposed to protect Fapta forever!
Gah!
Gabu!
It was that one!
Tall, ugly, beast-learned Gabu-run-set!
That one did it!
What to do?
Even if Fapta drives it away now...
It'll be back!
It's too much!
Arasa Bako Dundua?
Domeo?
Who are you, boy?
What are you doing?
Do not touch Gabu!
First time that we met, Fapta thought at Sosu.
That ornament on your head...
Looked so much like Gabu-run.
So Fapta was happy one of Gabu's allies.
Come to help Sosu.
I'm sorry, I...
I don't know what you mean.
Even though we couldn't communicate in words,
you protected us until Gabu began to move again.
The way you were so kind to me,
having met Fapta every single thing.
But you forget it all.
So long as the slimy things remain,
there'll be no end to this.
Where'd she go?
No, wait.
Is she...
She's behind me!
If beating your exterior does not work,
Fapta will try from inside Sosu.
Reg!
Remember now, Sosu.
Fapta not understand what you say, Sosu.
Sosu, do you remember anything yet?
Dammit!
Never do that again!
Never!
If you're truly a princess, show more grace!
Fapta is graceful, Sosu.
Even my words, just like you told me to!
Why would I tell you to speak in such a strange way?
That's not it, Sosu!
Fapta wise!
The boy wants to know if you are Fapta.
Gabu?
You can really understand the boy's language?
Kumu?
Igaragadu?
It is similar to that of those who pass through on occasion.
Huh?
The ones who carry around those stone people?
But this one is nice and isn't terrifying unlike those others that come around.
It's good.
Anyway, what are you?
Wagaramea?
I'm Reg.
R-E-G.
You're Reg?
So you are called Reg?
R-E-G.
Faun.
Noble maiden.
Opta.
Immortal one.
Together it is Fapta.
Princess who cannot perish!
You learn languages incredibly fast.
It's almost scary, really.
That so?
Gabu praised me for it too!
Hold it!
Why are you biting me?
Don't go in there!
Aren't you a princess?
Come on now, be a bit more graceful!
In your mother's tongue, it is considered graceful to add Sosu at the end of speech.
Fapta Sosu.
Just like this Sosu?
Splendid, Sosu.
Sosu!
Well, I...
I guess my mentor did say it's important...
To keep up appearances.
Fapta.
This is...
Well, um...
It's a symbol of friendship.
It would make me happy...
If you wore it.
I'm not...
Reg...
Smells like you, Sosu.
Aaaaaaah!
What's the matter?
Were you not going to stop Fapta Sosu?
I might pass out before I can actually start remembering anything.
The ceiling's caving in.
No!
I'm running out of time!
There's no telling how my body will react.
But I have to.
Riko!
Prujka!
Let's do this!
Huh?
You transform!
Why is that Sosu?
Sorry, but I'm taking you outside now!
You bad human child!
How dare you turn that kind stone person against me!
Against Fapta!
Wait a second...
Zuno Prujka?
It was Fapta who did it!
Who had Gabu deliver the stone person Sosu.
Why?
Would you do that?
The stone person wasn't able to say how trapped they felt Sosu.
It was you?
While we were sleeping, why'd you take it without saying anything?
Just do that!
It was a test!
That child helped the stone person without even bothering to sculpt them!
If that human child and the stone person are truly drawn to one another,
she'd find Mother!
Even if separated Sosu!
Rain?
No.
What is this?
After seeing Mother like this, your memories should have come back by now!
You should remember everything, Sosu!
That's unfortunate.
The iron rain has started to fall.
Wiko...
Damn.
There's already hardly anything left.
Hmm...
The village chief!
Is he protecting them from the rain?!
That is Fapta's mother, Sosu.
She's gigantic!
The burning rain doesn't bother her?
That mark...
Isn't it the same as Gabaroon's?
It's Haku, Sosu.
Fapta stuck those on, Sosu.
What's... Haku?
Haku.
What you attach to the Number One precious thing.
The Number One?
But you have two now!
Yes.
Fapta was born from 3 eggs, Sosu.
What's Haku?
What you attach to the Number One precious thing.
The Number One?
But you have two now!
Yes.
Fapta was born from 3 eggs, Sosu.
So can have up to 3.
I don't really get it.
But I guess that's how it is, huh?
That is how it is, Sosu.
Even though your mother's your most...precious...
Why is it you have to kill her?
As long as mother is alive and breathing, she will continue to be eaten away, Sosu.
If Fapta destroys the ones inside her, mother will once again find rest.
Just as a babe cannot return to the womb once they are born and grown,
Fapta cannot go inside mother.
Fapta has tried everything, but Fapta cannot pass through membrane Sosu.
Red.
Fapta is aware the village is full of activity, as well as possessing a developing culture.
What?
As Fapta cannot interact, I sometimes enter in her stead.
Despite this knowledge of activity and culture, Fapta says it is still something she must do.
Why?
That is how she is made.
It is her nature as a living creature.
Regis, you say you are not able to rewrite Sosu?
Yeah. This hand...
It emits such a powerful light.
But I can't really use it right now.
Cause I don't know what's gonna...
...happen if I fire it.
Fapta, I'm climbing up this pit because I'm also searching for Haku.
I was asked to do something.
Something I must do.
And after I am done, I'll definitely come back to you.
And my Haku will help me do it.
And I will rewrite however I can.
Thank you.
Sosu!
Fapta!
Got me more, Sosu!
What are you doing?
This is Reg, Sosu.
That's me?
Even after you leave on your journey, Fapta will talk to Reg.
So as not to forget you, Sosu.
Hm.
I should be able to get through that.
Reg...
Fapta...
Fapta is a princess, so...
Reg...
When you come back, stay with me forever.
And...
And then...
Babies.
I want something, too.
Let's make a promise.
When I come back, once we take care of you and your mother's destiny, we'll set off hand in hand.
Hand in hand.
And then...
We'll go on adventures!
See baby la...
She dee da...
How e la la...
창aleela...
Mag duel ae-la...
Mag Center...
I keep remembering, crying, laughing hard, filled with curiosity, such gentle facial expressions.
I can't remember any of the most important things we did, and maybe this is selfish of me to want, but you're going to burn yourself away till there's nothing left.
So how then, how can I possibly stop you?
Reg, you were kind, Sosu.
I bet.
But foolish Sosu.